We are so very excited to hear more about your program and how CLO has been used.
So I'm handing it over to you.
You can start whenever you are ready.
Okay, I start and sharing my screen.
Yes, please.
Okay, thank you for having me here.
I'm delighted to be here and I like to tell about my work and and what our work and what
our students are creating with CLO3D.
Yes, okay, that's the one, share it.
All right.
Hello, all people.
I don't see you, but please ask questions when you have questions at the end of the
Q&A.
That would be nice.
And I have a lot to tell.
I can't tell everything in short.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
I don't want to show everything in this presentation, but I try to show you a lot about what we
did.
All right.
Well, my presentation is back from real to virtual and vice versa, implementing 3D digital
protracting in a fashion curriculum and is from real to virtual and vice versa, because
we live in a real world in a 3D world and we can translate that to the digital, the
virtual.
Okay.
All right.
So I'm going to share a little bit, a little bit of what you said, what I learned in the
first place, and then I'm going to speak to the other people as well.
What I learned is just that when we talk about 3D machine, what we're talking about
in a virtual or virtual world, there are many things that are truly in the virtual world,
not what we're talking about in a 3D world that are actually in the virtual world.
So it's not a physical world.
And the 3D world is a physical world.
I think actually, I always talk about it.
In fact, I always talk about the physical world because the physical world, it's one
of the very important things in the virtual world.
So it's in a visual world, it's a place where you can like to exchange your thoughts with
your thoughts.
very, very important.
And she said, as computer 3D modeling allows designers
to think about this object,
this enables designers to concentrate on decisions
about objects rather than drawings.
What I said, we live in a 3D world, we think 3D.
But first I show some older developments,
the 3D revolution, curriculum developments.
I take the next slide.
Yes, this is not using 3D,
but there were some applications in 90s that, yeah,
there it was possible.
They started with the translation simulation in 3D.
We started a pilot in 2009.
No one didn't know anything about it
or wanted anything with it, but we wanted it.
So we wanted to have a pilot, 3D virtual prototyping
and probably near that point,
we wanted to make a mindset because it's also a mindset.
What am I looking at?
Is it real?
In this case, it was not real enough,
but we wanted to discover the possibilities for this.
Pattern construction, material training countries.
What was possible?
For Prince, it was ideal to show, to place them.
Students love this way of working.
It triggered them to concentrate on objects
and discover the new.
A lot of teachers were teaching,
in this minor and there were only two teachers
who knew about 3D.
So in the beginning, that was difficult.
Later on, we came together and a lot of teachers
who are skilled to teach that.
Until 2014, it wasn't really the future of fashion,
3D digital, but the future is now, not wait, just do.
Rethinking fashion in a sustainable and innovative way.
Our 3D digital outcomes were only not accurate enough.
We want, we want it better.
So we needed user-friendly professionals out there.
Reality in drape, look and feel, avatars, tools to,
and tools to enlarge, to create the freedom of creation.
Because I worked, this we worked out in the design department.
And you see, the students needed, you know,
the design department. And you see, the students needed,
to create all that they made in real.
And they had the digital process.
It was a combination of these two.
Because that we find most beautiful.
Well, through the combination of traditional
and innovative digital software,
of digital craftsmanship, the hypercrafts,
a new generation of designers is born.
And that is really true.
It's a new generation.
I'm an older than the other generation,
and I love it still.
But the 3D digital revolution came to Amphib.
And I wanted to know more about why the students wanted
this kind of work, this working method.
What was so interesting in that 3D simulation?
So I researched the influence of digital technology,
3D simulation technology, on the fashion design process,
and the consequences for education.
Because that was necessary.
What needed we, what needed Amphib to do to facilitate this work?
And because I saw it, I saw the students doing it,
but there were not many teachers at that moment
that were able to understand what we're doing.
But what you see is,
that there is a traditional design cycle,
and it has, and there is a 3D digital design cycle.
It has a lot of, a big influence on your,
the way you think, the way you act in that moment.
There's a high density of ideas from the start.
There's an overview on the entire plan,
and interaction, decision-making,
are they, the divine products, unique,
unique 3D products are coming up.
And 25% more design time.
That was what I, what I researched.
And so it's, it's merging together.
That is because of the 3D simulation.
We see what's happening,
and it can detect failures in the early stage well.
I had, I did my master's,
and I also did an interdisciplinary project.
We set it up with a lecturer and students,
and industry part, industry.
Partners from the Felder, Lingerie company,
and Jakob Kock.
And we made a comparison analysis,
with different, diverse, diverse software, 3D software.
And we discovered at that moment,
2014, Pro3D was the most user-friendly, intuitive,
very important, future-proof software
for design, production, and marketing.
We started with that.
We started with that design and production later.
But the process was more self-steering.
An overview on the entire plan.
Detect failures in an early stage.
We already know it now.
3D simulation and the render qualities were very accurate,
and real, and showed realism.
By then also, but now it's, it's more, much more user-friendly,
intuitive, and what we saw was steep learning curve.
That was also important.
And we saw that with the students.
Here, this was, that research product,
came out the first live virtual fashion show.
Students, well, were researching how can virtual simulation
help to extend the way of fashion presentation,
and how can we use virtual simulation
to make fashion design processes more sustainable?
Because sustainability,
is a very important one.
In this project, Amber J. Slaughter,
known as one of the fabricants,
probably you know about her.
She was looking for a project that said,
come on, join us.
And this is her collection,
what was showed in 3D environment.
Okay.
There were, because we were able to use Go3D,
students were loving it.
Okay. There were, because we were able to use Go3D, students were loving it.
In 2016, left the graduation show,
digital and digital collections created with Glow.
Here left Amber J. Slaughter,
she made a hologram motion capture.
There were a lot of experiments.
And digital only,
she didn't want to produce garments in real.
Zylva Stelava, a digital designer,
an entrepreneur.
She adapted the principle of no waste.
And she created a collection
cutting out the pattern
and using all the waste patterns in her collection.
using all the waste patterns in her collection.
Ellie-G. Pom now is working as a designer at ING.
She created her whole collection in 3D and also
created it in real she learned cloud in i think three weeks she was so quick she said i think
i'm going to do it and then when next time i spoke to her she had already three prototypes
digital and tamara koff she's a three designer head of designer adidas she also had a very
lovely collection nice movements this was really heaven for the students to work with
glow the first time graduates were it made it it made it possible for graduates to graduate
in three collections this is lula's color these are the patterns and the leftovers
every piece she took every piece she used we worked on this movie together
with one of the families
and here she made three different outfits and experimented with movement
and showed her
transformation pattern and leftovers
a nice small collection
which is
in between chaos i think
all right go to the next the company that inspired me very much was atokak at that moment 2019
they were open source rethinking the way to design present sell and produced produce and that was for
me a partner
because i could talk with them about our developments and their developments
what they showed is traditional process and digitized process maybe you know already but
it's significant it's a significant difference 18 months or one month and in a digitized process
we don't have that stock because in their process you design the pattern etc
you present it in 3d render it in nice quality clothings for all their products
and then you sell on the amount when you have enough you can produce so those new ways of
working new business models they're so important and they were the first ones who came up with that
it was really interesting for us
and i think that proof of concept is it really working
is it really true what i'm seeing is it really possible to realize
students want to do that as well let's compare it with the denim if they
need to if they do the denim miner they want to make a real denim later on making
they know they can do it and um they're free to challenge themselves in a different way but there
was no
So the whole collection, he made six, he made nice outfits for his friends, his six friends
that also showed the products, the outfits.
And he had a collage modular design experiments or so from Winklow, the modular tool.
And he designed digital 12-in-1s.
He was very exact, very precise, measured everyone, measured up the friends, made a
body scanner.
We have a body scanner, you see.
And so he could do that in a very professional way.
And he made 12-in-1s, then figure out a drape, testing a drape of the fabric, that is, of
course, very important.
And then without a prototype, he just realized it.
And showed it on the catalog.
And that was important also for the teachers to say, well, okay, this is possible, although
they didn't understand the process in the beginning, from the start.
But it's important to take people with you that they understand what you're doing, because
it is quite abstract for people who are not working with it.
Curriculum developments.
These turntables are very easy.
They're nice.
But in clothing, you make it in a minute, if you have a nice garment.
And I like to play around with them in my presentation.
We have the University of Applied Science, our bigger group, the Amsterdam Fashion Institute.
We exist since 1952.
Amphi has three dimensions, fashion design, fashion business and development, and fashion
branding students.
It's the only bachelor degree program in the Netherlands to cover the environment.
The Netherlands to cover the entire fashion chain, programs in Dutch and in English.
And Amphi invites every year 350 new students, with also dropouts, of course, and that's
in every study, 1,100 students study fashion at Amphi from 54 countries.
That's an interesting international community.
Thank you.
We have the lecturers, fashion, research, and technology.
They're scientific and artistic based.
We have Mr. and Dr. plugins and core is data as a message of material, future means of
thinking, future ways of learning.
How do we wear digital fashion?
Now it's pop art.
You didn't know that, actually.
know that that would become a hot item but that is um yeah it's digital physical
and critical critical making is for ourselves so very important we have a field lab 3d knit
a lot more but i continue the curriculum structure is this a lot of information you
have to read it from year one year two and then go to year three four graduation
this is the foundation year one with some labs they're diverse then year two and year three
industrial industry internship and we have minor and specialization
i'm the office of four-year bachelor study starting year has two semesters each 20 weeks
a minor specialization and internship just one semester and i focus i i zoom a
on what we're doing there this is year two and year three i show you later on some um
information i give you some information about the industry internship the minor specialization
what i wanted to show is in red classes are included we also want to have that in the first
year that's a whole uh in whole year two we have three hours a week the club classes and and then a
to the project that we're in.
The minor and specialization,
we have individuals, I'll show you some,
3D hypergraphs, very famous because that was
where we started with.
Fashion and denim production in Europe also have 3D.
And also there are now a lot of industry partners
that can, that all want to implement 3D or do already.
And students can do that a lot.
In the beginning it was not, but now.
It's, that is really very good.
And the blue one is developing.
Brands, branding is still developing.
They're doing it, but still developing to implement
both 3D and minor in that program.
And of course in orange, if students have that knowledge
from year two,
they can apply it in their process and that they do.
What I will say is learning by doing,
not speaking about it, just do it, do it.
Get behind your computer and open Clo and make it, create it.
There's a lot of information, magic material
that Clo already created.
And you can go to their YouTube channel
and you also always can Google, okay,
how to insert a zipper.
You get a lot of hits, but this is naturally by doing.
This is, you see a sketch,
you see a 12 in Clo for this project,
small project, learning by doing.
All students map that process each semester
from start to end product.
It's to communicate and reflect on their learning process.
Show the tools, techniques, working method,
design experiments, et cetera.
That's important.
This is an eyelet create with the straps in a hoodie
that they also had to create and they reflect on it.
Also on there, well, do they like it or not?
So what's the bigger picture?
What's happening?
Finding articles about 3D developments.
This is just a lookbook from a student at a camp.
She shows a silhouette, her first design.
She made really interesting,
digital sculptures with the bodies.
And then later on designed her outfit on it.
And with all kinds of experiments,
she was able to create it in digital.
It was a complete digital graduation project.
Well, what we see with the 3D revolution
and the implementation that there's a new vocabulary,
the 3D model,
that kind of image,
I guess the model that was really important.
We really need to learn how to place them.
We really need to learn how to blend it.
That is what we already know,
but we needed to do it and that we have to share finding
because we came up,
come across so many different systems
that we need to share it,
to tell, to talk about it,
internet launching and closing the instruction videos and youtube of course and don't forget
the manuals because they're great new vocabulary like texturing it's not only buying a fabric
it is um yeah making a texture map a normal map a displacement map so it's a whole new way of working
and this is they don't understand in one go you have to repeat it and then when they create it
when they're doing it and they show it and what i said learning curve is steep we can personalize
our digital fabric we can do whatever we want and um well let's see if we need it for design only
in a digital world for production you just have the possibilities to source it understand and what
i what i really love is the schematic render schematic render yeah what surrender a lot of
people don't know what it is
so that is the vocabulary that we need to uh to learn a mesh what's a match
but the schematic render you already saw it this is an easy one uh just only the top of the trouser
that is created for the bottoms and the top stitches and all in why make a flat drawing
when you have a 3d product already and that is what uh what also student research a research but
i'm so
glad that's a that's a clue came up with this schematic render
well in year two um one of the assignments is the end of end of the first period
they create a small collection so they have to make drawings like this one you have to make a
drawing then they have to realize it pattern making you know they have sewing classes etc
fabric classes and then they recreate it and make a digital queen twin they recreate it and so and then
so that this is a good very good learning part of the learning process we collaborated with
industry partners like h m burley north face and more that is very motivating for the students
and what is the bigger picture well going into the real world let's say because on the in
the end of the day it's a bubble uh and uh we have to get out and see what's happening in the world
matthias of publica see he set up the skills the an overview on the skills from on feed
especially prepared him for his internship and he said well basics of close 3d and presentation
garment construction basic pattern pattern assembly that is an important
in the first two years our direction how to design how to design from concept
and learn about materials etc and industry production focused tasks that is in
second year second semester yes internship was also patterns and um well these are all
names from companies that love to have our students as interns our students have a lot of
a lot of skills and a lot of knowledge about 3d it's it's a topic already for a long time so it's
really developed um for students graduates or h m or one is working on vivian westworldings
well year three and four it's a flexible program program and there's also an innovation program
called the vision studio they work with the industry design the future for and with the
industry in this reality school where the 3d dimensions work together branders managers
designers sometimes well sometimes mostly um there is research questions from the industry partners
that didn't start 3d yet with 3d yet so uh we also introduce it to them and
and see what kind of product they have and of course they need the experiment for the students
but there it's also with fashion business and development students and branding students
so they are um defining their role their new role as a 3d fashion zone and a 3d digital fashion
brand so that is a development that's very important for the companies uh and for the
students well in year three and four flexible program this was already 2020 minor hypercraft
and a collection made by laura slings and what she did she made a fashion picture collection
we developed
an independent and experimental culture collection what she she she wanted to luxury
brand storytelling be careful what you wish for is criticizing social obstruction by the rich
so what you see is at the end she looks very happy in her smooth nice
simple dress and don't which wish too much well whatever she did she had a very good
research and she created this for uh intel everything you see is created and come from
start to end also with the assets that are on the the the garment and the nice lace that she created
it was a really interesting one and another more technical project is an
fine new design methods for upcycling for instance smart and sustainable research the technical good
goal was to explore if Co3D can be used as a tool to design from existing materials.
It was a fashion collection for urban beach commerce and what you see is that she has
developed a technique to place the special diversity in fabrics and how it would fit,
how it would work in the presentation. Here she showed different pattern pieces
and also some extended fuse here. At last she had beautiful renders created in Clio and all these
trims she made herself. Also said what I like is that I can still make changes to my design before
having to cut it into the material so that I can evaluate whether
this material is suitable or not. Also making an inlay like this is clearer and easier than I
can imagine in real life and a very interesting one. If we talk about communication, in fact
vocabulary and online tools for production, it's also important to define important ingredients
for digital fashion or for production in real by using Clio. And students are also experimenting
with Clio. If we for production, it is clear how we can communicate and Clio helps the companies
to do so. It's really, really interesting. Everything is in and nice renderings with
tech pack and the bomber materials. But if you would communicate a digital fashion,
well, how are you communicating this? Well, you need parameters for the fabrics, for instance,
what kind of matching?
What kind of
extra details texturing used? And of course, also how it is connected, how it is assembled,
some extended few. So we are also thinking not only in production in real, but also in production
from a digital environment. The fashion industry needs new people with digital craft and
still been there for a long period of time. Which is a very interesting idea.
And I think it's a really important tool to be able to navigate. And it does take some
of the data from those companies that are still there in the world. But I think it's
really interesting to do a lot more data with from a very top level perspective.
And I think if this is something that's up to you to use and you don't want to spend
your time thinking, well, this is so-and-so, and this is a game. It can be amazing.
And I think there's so much more in these kinds of resources.
And if you could put it into the bag, how would you choose it?
Because it's a very traditional way of thinking.
So I think digital marketing, this is a very, very interesting and there's a few
other questions here that I can answer, but I'm going to say another one now.
fitting now on the hooky avatar and so know about pattern know how to assemble material texturing is
a very important one you want to have it realistic drape and touch look and feel then automatic
automized methods know about the automized methods i showed you but for instance please
creating please it's so such fun and serious in close 3d that students take that possibility and
make them make their uh yeah apply it in their collection designers now you see in collections
they don't realize you see much more please than you saw before because it is also optimized and
you can create it as you please you just do a digital that is really
it like a puffer you see a lot of variation in puffer jackets because that is easy to
create a closure here this was a student that oh wow she was so precise in that but it's
important the details also in the digital um also the the garments that created for the
as digital fashion details make uh tell a story about the
garments
they give it character and that is important well we go to
more of our change makers and uh skill set above critical thinking digital literacy and
craftsmanship software flexibility conscious design decision making respect for craft
create value not for own products i think that is we think that is an important skill set
um for students that for people that are working in this area and um as you saw the first um
projects of uh amber jay slotan but go to visit the fabricant the digital fashion house
they they want they were wasting nothing but data igniting a fashion revolution through
co-creation with the status quo they are a community they want to learn each other
feedback of their users co-create experience enjoy it's a marketplace community they want to share
knowledge also share income you create an mft for instance they do it together they
tell people how to do it and they can mint it uh use blockchain mint it and
then it is uh it is a shared a shared creation it's interesting very nice they make clothes
that are always digital metaphysical that principle they kept um augmented reality come back to that
later we also saw the jews of uh for stolova these are going to shoot it out digital samples to
reduce weight reuse waste and clean circularly
um she is into making beautiful renders from special um people not average and uh she is
reusing everything that blouses and jackets have in she is re-assembling that and making having her
own style in her garments and she is re-assembling that and making having her own style in her garments
design doing everything 3d using clone of course students are
creating their own project these are graduate projects graduation and every
everyone can make his own projects in the last half year of the study some focus on the digital
fashion care label on digital waste can we replace a technical drawing well the answer we
know now that claire was coming up with um yes we can this was a beautiful uh presentation
this is a session management students she wrote a thesis about how luxury brands prepare for the
metaphors we are at the beginning of shaping new digital worlds she wants to do it for web
three or four in web four touch and feel will be there so she made outfits that people can survive
in that uh in that before an interesting one beautiful technical very good created uh also a
nice digital fashion collapse capsule collection helping one's smooth transition from offline to
online your virtual twin this is a chair and a garment in itself and uh makes you uh having the
transition from off night to online also created all by lily shillings
well we have graduates entrepreneurs find niches and push 3d innovation forward
as lingerie where the development of soft tissue avatars is important for the fit
rosa kramer set up this hyper birth studio sources a graduate
and you know
Now she has six people as personnel, she just started two years ago.
We go to the next and then we see Sarah Meyer, you saw them in the second video, and she
first worked in the fashion industry and now she's a vegan virtual artist, face filters
on Pinkradia 2015, she is, well, it's amazing what she's creating, I have some links here,
most of all, but Chloe, I saw Chloe's calling all creators get the chance to make your 3D
garments into AR filter, go to Chloe Connects, so if you want to know more about that, but
this is interesting, she has a good website where you also, where you can try out the
face filters she made.
Well this is, again, from real to virtual, vice versa.
I always like to end with this joyful, with a joyful movie he created.
He used wasted inflatables, reused it, the process is experimental and technical, personal
signature, very personal.
All done.
The garments and assets were designed and created in close-review and executed in real
by the designer.
He graduated last year and he also won the prize of best of all universities in Holland,
so that's very great.
You see him struggling, finding this flamingo, how can I add that in a pattern and what is
needed, what other material is needed, so it is really interesting to do that in Chloe.
It really works and immediately gives you feedback in your 3D simulation.
Okay, next is the video, and maybe you have sound, I hope so, and otherwise enjoy.
Okay.
Nice.
Good, awesome.
Thank you.
It was just it's short, but it is so intense.
Nice.
Yes.
So.
Yeah.
all the materials he made me it's it's incredible a lot of prints nice um well
i hope you understand a bit of my talking and you liked it but thanks and for listening